We have put together some functionality inside of our MCP server but we have no idea if it works
so it'd be really great if we could test this out somehow. It turns out that by using this Python
SDK we automatically get access to an in-browser debugger so we can make sure that this server is
working as expected. Let me show you how to use it really quickly. Back inside my terminal,
I'm going to make sure that I have my Python environment activated. Remember the readme
document goes into detail on the exact command to run to make sure that you have activated that
environment. Once you are sure that it is activated we'll run mcp dev and then the
name of the file that contains our server. In this case it is mcpserver.py. Once I run that I'll then
be told that I have a server listening on port 6277 and I'll be given a direct address to actually
access it. I'm going to open up that address inside my browser and once you go there you'll
see something that looks like this. This is the MCP inspector. Now right away there's something
important I want you to understand here. This inspector is in active development so by the time
you are watching this video what you see on the screen right now might be very very different than
what I am showing. Nonetheless it's probably still going to have some very similar functionality.
On the left hand side you'll see a connect button. That is going to start up your MCP
server so that file that we just edited. I'm going to click on connect and then right away
we'll see a couple of different things on the screen appear. I first want you to notice the
top menu bar up here. It lists out resources, prompts, tools and some other stuff. Again the
UI might change by the time you watch this video so if you do not see this menu bar up here all we
are really looking for here is some tools section. Once I click on tools I will click on list tools
and we'll see the name of the tools that we just put together. If I click on one the right hand
panel is then going to change and I can use this panel over here to manually invoke one of my tools
to make sure that it is working as expected. So this is how we can do some live development
on our MCP server without actually having to wire it up to a real application. In order to
use the read doc contents tool all we have to do is put in a document ID. If I go back over to my
editor and go up to the docs dictionary right here I can copy one of these document IDs so I
will take out deposition.md. I will put it in as the doc ID and then click on run tool. I should
then see run tool of success with the contents of the document and that is it right there. I can
verify it it's the same exact string as what I see right there. We can use this same exact technique
to test out the other tool as well. So I will change over to the edit document tool now I'll
put in my document ID my old string that I want to replace. How about we replace the word deposition
actually how about an easier word to type out how about just this that'll be a little bit easier. So
my old string is this remember that is going to be capital sensitive and I'm going to replace it with
a report and if I run the tool I'll then be given a success. Remember that tool does not actually
return the document's contents it just edits the document. So now to verify the edit was done
correctly I can go back over to the read doc contents tool run that one again with the same
document ID and I should see a report deposition and then blah blah blah. All right so as you can
see this MCP inspector allows us to very easily debug a MCP server that we are implementing
without actually having to wire the server up to an actual application. As you start building your
own MCP servers I expect you'll be using this inspector tool quite a bit and we'll probably
use it a little bit more inside of this module just to make sure that our server development
is going along pretty well.